<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Newport</string>
    <string name="details_activity">Details</string>

    <!-- Image descriptions -->
    <string name="image_description">Newport image</string>
    <string name="image_background_description">Background for opaque image</string>

    <!-- Sights Fragment -->
    <string name="yaquina_bridge_name">Yaquina Bay Bridge</string>
    <string name="yaquina_bridge_distance">Yaquina Bay, Newport</string>
    <string name="yaquina_bridge_details">Historic bridge built in 1934</string>
    <string name="yaquina_bridge_description">Being one of the most photographed bridges designed by Conde McCullough,
        it took 2 years and over $1 million to build. It is constructed with both steel and concrete arches and is tall
        enough for most boats to pass underneath. Art Deco and Art Monderne design motifs and Gothic architecture inspired
        the style of the bridge. At each end of the bridge are pedestrian plazas with stairways accessing observation areas.</string>
    <string name="yaquina_bridge_location">1950 Southwest Coast Highway, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="yaquina_head_name">Yaquina Head Lighthouse</string>
    <string name="yaquina_head_distance">3.8 miles north of Newport</string>
    <string name="yaquina_head_detail">Oregon\'s tallest lighthouse in operation since 1873</string>
    <string name="yaquina_head_description">Standing at 93 feet, Yaquina Head was built in Paris of 1868 using more than
        370,000 bricks. Today, it is still actively shining its rotating light using the original French lens.
        During World War II, 17 servicemen were stationed at Yaquina Head to look out for enemy ships. The lighthouse is open
        for regular tours year round. See blm.gov/learn/interpretive-centers/yaquina for more details.</string>
    <string name="yaquina_head_location">750 Northwest Lighthouse Drive, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="yaquina_bay_name">Yaquina Bay Lighthouse</string>
    <string name="yaquina_bay_distance">1.2 miles south of Newport</string>
    <string name="yaquina_bay_detail">Oregon\'s only wooden lighthouse in operation for 3 years</string>
    <string name="yaquina_bay_description">Built in 1871 soon after the founding of Newport, it was active for 3 years
        until Yaquina Head was built. Standing at 39.6 feet, it is the only Oregon lighthouse with the living quarters
        attached to the light. It was scheduled for demolition in 1946, but after a long battle it was recongized as a
        historical site. Self-guided tours are free and donations are accepted. See yaquinalights.org for hours.</string>
    <string name="yaquina_bay_location">North End of Yaquina Bay, Newport, OR 97365-1347</string>

    <string name="yaquina_beach_name">Yaquina Bay State Recreation Site</string>
    <string name="yaquina_beach_distance">1.2 miles south of Newport</string>
    <string name="yaquina_beach_detail">Grassy area to picnic near Yaquina Bay Lighthouse with beach access</string>
    <string name="yaquina_beach_description">Established in 1948, this site includes picnic facilities, a forested bluff,
        a fisherman\'s memorial shrine, and beach access. It is great for swimming, fishing, and hiking as well.</string>
    <string name="yaquina_beach_location">Yaquina Bay State Recreation Site, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="foulweather_name">Cape Foulweather</string>
    <string name="foulweather_distance">11 miles north of Newport</string>
    <string name="foulweater_detail">Panoramic views where storm winds can reach 100 mph</string>
    <string name="foulweather_description">Named by Captain James Cook in 1778 on a day of inclement weather,
        this 500-foot basalt can be seen from Otter Crest State Scenic Viewpoint. Nearby are Otter Crest, Devil\'s
        Punchbowl, Moolack and Beverly beaches, Gull Rock and Yaquina Head.</string>
    <string name="foulweater_location">4905 Otter Crest Loop, Depoe Bay, OR 97341</string>

    <string name="depoe_bay_name">Depoe Bay</string>
    <string name="depoe_bay_distance">13 miles north of Newport</string>
    <string name="depoe_bay_detail">World\'s smallest naviagable harbor</string>
    <string name="depoe_bay_descrption">Home to 1,400 residents, Depoe Bay is right against the ocean, a sea wall running almost the
    whole length of town. Here, you can watch waves crash against the "spouting horn" rock formations or watch for whales. A Whale
    Watching Center provides an indoor lookout and information about when the whales are passing through. On the other side, the harbor
    is home to charter fishing and whale-watching boats, and on land, various shops and restaurants line Highway 101.</string>
    <string name="depoe_bay_location">Oregon Coast Highway, Depoe Bay, OR 97341</string>

    <string name="ocean_shore_name">Ocean Shore State Recreation Area</string>
    <string name="ocean_shore_distance">0.5 miles west of Newport</string>
    <string name="ocean_shore_detail">Beach access with hiking trails, tide pools and picnic areas</string>
    <string name="ocean_shore_description">An oceanfront park that offers hiking and picnic areas, as well as tide
        pools and wildlife viewing. The entrance is wheelchair accessible and amenities are good for kids. This beach
        is also great for flying kites.</string>
    <string name="ocean_shore_location">Ocean Shore State Recreation Area, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <!-- Activities Fragment -->
    <string name="aquarium_name">Oregon Coast Aquarium</string>
    <string name="aquarium_distance">2.2 miles south of Newport in South Beach</string>
    <string name="aquarium_detail">A world class facility showcasing\ndeep sea creatures</string>
    <string name="aquarium_description">Rated as one of the nation\'s top 10 aquariums, Oregon Coast Aquarium has indoor
    and outdoor exhibits with various animals. Paths lead you through the octopus cave, sea aviary, and viewing pools
    where otters, seals, and sea lions reside. The "Passages of the Deep" exhibit contains an underwater acrylic tunnel
    where visitors are surrounded by sharks, bat rays, and more. Open pools are available for visitors to experience
        the touch of coral and reef-residing creatures. See aquarium.org for more details.</string>
    <string name="aquarium_location">2820 Southeast Ferry Slip Road, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="marine_tours_name">Marine Discovery Tours</string>
    <string name="marine_tours_distance">Town of Newport</string>
    <string name="marine_tours_detail">Whale watching and sea life boat tours</string>
    <string name="marine_tours_description">Through the months of March and October, daily tours are offered for Whale Watching
    and Sea Life Cruises. Being family owned and operated, guides provide a fun narration about the ocean, Yaquina Bay and River,
    while looking out for wildlife ranging from harbor porpoises to bald eagles. See marinediscoverytours.com for more details. </string>
    <string name="marine_tours_location">345 Southwest Bay Boulevard, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="tradewinds_name">Tradewinds Charters</string>
    <string name="tradewinds_distance">Depoe Bay</string>
    <string name="tradewinds_detail">Whale watching and deep sea fishing tours</string>
    <string name="tradewinds_description">Located right across the street from the Whale Watching Center, Tradewinds Charters
    have been in operation since 1938. Tours provided are whale watching, sportfishing, bird watching, and ecology tours. Boats are modern
    and fully equipped, along with an experienced, knowledgeable, and friendly captains and crew.
    See tradewindscharters.com for more details.</string>
    <string name="tradewinds_location">118 Highway 101, Depoe Bay, OR 97341</string>

    <string name="winery_name">Depoe Bay Winery</string>
    <string name="winery_distance">Depoe Bay</string>
    <string name="winery_detail">Wine tasting and sales on the waterfront</string>
    <string name="winery_description">Open 10-6 every day, Depoe Bay Winery offers a wide selection of wine tasting alongside the oceanfront.
    The ceiling of the shop is covered with hanging dollar bills, all signed for local charities along the Central Coast. Concerts, BBQs and pig
    roasts are often on the agenda at the winery. Wine can be shipped to your door, some specials including free shipping.
    See depoebaywinery.com for more details.</string>
    <string name="winery_location">22 Southeast Highway 101, Depoe Bay, OR 97341</string>

    <string name="dockside_name">Dockside Charters</string>
    <string name="dockside_distance">Depoe Bay</string>
    <string name="dockside_detail">Largest charter fishing fleet on the Oregon Coast</string>
    <string name="dockside_description">Tuna fishing, whale watching, and sight seeing cruises are offered daily. Boats are clean and maintained,
    providing comfortable adventures. Depending on the season, fishing trips offer bottom fishing for Ling Cod and Rock Fish, Halibut, Salmon, and
    Albacore Tuna. Dungeness Crab fishing options are offered as well. See docksidedepoebay.com for more details.</string>
    <string name="dockside_location">270 Coast Guard Drive, Depoe Bay, OR 97341</string>

    <!-- Lodging Fragment -->
    <string name="anchor_pier_name">Anchor Pier Lodge</string>
    <string name="anchor_pier_distance">Town of Newport</string>
    <string name="anchor_pier_detail">Waterfront rooms with private decks and fireplaces</string>
    <string name="anchor_pier_description">Located along Newport\'s Historic Bayfront, guest rooms are spacious with relaxing nautical-themed decor
        and private decks overlooking the harbor. Guests are offered walk-in showers or spa rooms with jet tubs and showers, along with euro-top
    mattresses. Rooms contain fireplaces, microwaves, a coffee and tea center, mini-fridge, hair dryers and bathing supplies, Wi-Fi, and cable TV.
    See anchorpierlodge.com for more details.</string>
    <string name="anchor_pier_location">345 Southwest Bay Boulevard, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="rv_park_name">Port of Newport RV Park and Marina</string>
    <string name="rv_park_distance">2.5 miles south of Newport in South Beach</string>
    <string name="rv_park_detail">Open year round with a view of Yaquina Bridge with full services</string>
    <string name="rv_park_description">If trailering is your vacationing style, visit the Port of Newport RV park. Right along the water of the bay,
    visitors have a close view of Yaquina Bay Bridge and a short walk to the marina. Full hook-ups are provided for all 143 spaces, many designed for big
    rigs. Showers, laundry rooms are provided, as well as limited Wi-Fi. Oregon Coast Aquarium, Hatfield Marine Science Center, Newport Marina Store and Charters
    and Rogue Brewery and Rogue Distillery are all within walking distance. See portofnewport.com for more details.</string>
    <string name="rv_park_location">2120 Southeast Marine Science Drive, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="resort_name">Embarcadero Resort Hotel and Marina</string>
    <string name="resort_distance">1 mile east of Newport</string>
    <string name="resort_detail">Resort with views of Yaquina Bay, a restaurant and indoor pool</string>
    <string name="resort_description">Tucked away at the end of Newport\’s Historic Bayfront, Embarcadero Resort offers 60 well-appointed guest rooms and suites
    with private balconies overlooking Yaquina Bay. For boaters, a private marina offers charter fishing and boat rentals, as well as a private crab dock with
    crab boat and pot rentals. Food and drink amenities include a bar and free BBQ facilities. For those that want to relax, a free spa and wellness center is
    offered, with two outdoor spas, sauna, and fitness center. An indoor salt water pool is also on site. See embarcaderoresort.com/en-gb for more details.</string>
    <string name="resort_location">1000 Southeast Bay Boulevard, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <!-- Food Fragment -->
    <string name="ocean_bleu_name">Ocean Bleu at Gino\'s</string>
    <string name="ocean_bleu_distance">Town of Newport</string>
    <string name="ocean_bleu_detail">Seafood cafe and fish market sourced from local fish</string>
    <string name="ocean_bleu_description">In the heart of Newport\'s Historic Bayfront is located this cozy restaurant serving fresh local fish. Popular for their
    popcorn shrimp, Ocean Bleu serves seafood such as scallops, clams, crab, shrimp, fish and chips, as well as soups, salads, and sandwiches of many varieties.
    Desserts offered include Gino\'s cheesecake, molten lava chocolate cake, and berry cobbler. Outdoor seating is available.
    See oceanbleuseafoods.com for more details.</string>
    <string name="ocean_bleu_location">808 Southwest Bay Boulevard, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="rogue_name">Rogue Ales and Spirits Brewery</string>
    <string name="rogue_distance">1.9 miles south of Newport</string>
    <string name="rogue_detail">Serves handcrafted beers and hamburgers in a family-friendly setting</string>
    <string name="rogue_description">Tour the Rogue Brewery Distillery while walking to the upstairs restaurant that overlooks the
    Port of Newport Marina. The menu serves meals such as hamburgers, fish and chips, pizza, sandwiches, soup and salad, and of course,
    a wide variety of beer. Vegetarian and vegan meals are offered. See rogue.com for more details.</string>
    <string name="rogue_location">2320 Southeast Marine Science Drive, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="sea_hag_name">Gracie\'s Sea Hag</string>
    <string name="sea_hag_distance">Depoe Bay</string>
    <string name="sea_hag_detail">Cozy seafood restaurant with bar and music</string>
    <string name="sea_hag_description">Being a local favorite in Depoe Bay since 1963, the Sea Hag provides a nautical atmosphere
    while serving fish and chips, clams, soup and salad, pastas, sandwiches, and more of many varieties. A bar featuring live music
    is separated from the main restaurant. See theseahag.com for more details.</string>
    <string name="sea_hag_location">58 Highway 101, Depoe Bay, OR 97341</string>

    <!-- Events Fragment -->
    <string name="market_name">Newport Saturday Farmers Market</string>
    <string name="market_distance">Town of Newport</string>
    <string name="market_detail">Features 70 vendors for seasonal produce, art and live music</string>
    <string name="market_description">Since 1978, this market has been offering a variety of items year-round. It features 70 vendors
    offering seasonal produce, art, fresh flowers, plants, jewelry, photography, hot food, fresh pastries, honey, salsas, coffee, crafts,
    and live music. Provided with Oregon\'s abundant growing season, farmers bring diverse, high-quality local produce, meat, eggs, and honey.
    The outdoor summer and fall market is every Saturday from May 12th to October and is located on the corner of Highway 101 and Angle St.
    The indoor winter and spring market is every Saturday from November to April and is located at the Lincoln County Fairgrounds Exhibit Hall.
    See newportfarmersmarket.org for more details.</string>
    <string name="market_location">101 and Southwest Angle Street, Newport, OR 97365\nor 633 Northeast 3rd Street, Newport, OR 97365</string>

    <string name="whale_name">Whale Watching</string>
    <string name="whale_distance">Depoe Bay</string>
    <string name="whale_detail">Visit the Whale Watching Center during migration peaks</string>
    <string name="whale_description">Whales can be seen along the Oregon Coast year-round, but twice a year about 20,000 gray whales make their
    journey along the coast. During the months of late December and early January, the southward migration peak takes the whales from the Bering
    and Chukchi seas near Alaska down to Baja California, Mexico. The second migration peak begins in late March, where whales, along with babies
    born in the warm seas, begin their journey back to Alaska. During these peaks, Oregon State Parks offers Whale Watching Week. At each whale
    watching site, volunteers are available to provide information to visitors and help identify whales through the use of spotting scopes. See
    whalespoken.org for more details.</string>
    <string name="whale_location">119 Highway 101, Depoe Bay, OR 97341</string>

    <string name="washington_name">Lady Washington</string>
    <string name="washington_distance">Port of Newport</string>
    <string name="washington_detail">Keep a lookout for this historic ship sailing into town</string>
    <string name="washington_description">Though only a replica, Lady Washington continues to bring interest to the original historic ship that sailed
    the seas in the 18th century. After the Revolutionary War in 1787, she was refitted for a trading voyage around Cape Horn. A year later,
    she became the first American ship to reach land on the west coast and sail to Honolulu, Hong Kong and Japan. Here, she was used for black pearl and sandalwood
    trade. Ironically, centuries later, the replica was used in Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl, as well as Star Trek: Generations,
    Once Upon a Time, and Revolution. Upon construction of the Lady Washington replica, historians researched the ship thoroughly, while skilled shipwrights
    built the ship, according to tradition. Don\'t forget to check out her sister ship, the Hawaiian Chieftain. Visit historicalseaport.org for more information,
    including times and locations.</string>
    <string name="washington_location">600 Southeast Bay Boulevard Newport, OR 97365</string>

</resources>
